mathforum.org 2016-03-05

# Math Forum: Privacy Policy

If you are under 13, please have your parents/guardians read this policy and approve your use of our services. If you are under 13 and you participate in the Problem of the Week services or subscribe to any other Math Forum services, please have your teacher or parent register you for participation. At any time, your parents have the right to request that we remove your personal information by e-mailing us or by contacting us via postal mail or telephone (800)756-7823.

### Privacy Policy:

This is how we will handle information that we learn about you from your visit to our Web site. The information we receive depends upon what you do when visiting our site.

If you visit our site to read or download information from our Web pages:

  * We collect and keep track of only the following information about you: the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com); the date and time you access our site; and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our site. We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address may also be used to customize the information that you receive in order to make it most relevant to you.
  * We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, to help us make our site more useful to visitors, and to place advertisements and sponsorships that enable us to continue to offer our services free of charge.

If you identify yourself by sending an email or by providing your email address in order to participate in one of our services such as Ask Dr. Math, Problems of the Week, Teacher2Teacher, mailing lists and discussion groups, the Math Forum Internet Newsletter, and our Webmaster and online help:

  * We use personal identifying information from users in various ways to provide the educational services and support you seek. We use your email address in order to respond to your questions and submissions or to maintain your subscriptions. We also use email in order to identify who you are and make it easy for you to be a regular user of one of our mentored services.
  * From time to time we conduct surveys of users for the purpose of evaluating the use of our Web site, and we may use your information to contact you for more information.
  * When we archive and publish solutions from the Problem of the Week services, we publish at most the first name and initial letter of the surname of the students and schools with noteworthy submissions on our Web pages, and these may be read by the general public. Teachers who have registered for a Problem of the Week "teacher account" with us may also view information concerning the number and date of submissions entered by students from their school to the Problem of the Week projects. We publish selected questions and responses from Ask Dr. Math, Teacher2Teacher, and other services. Services such as Virtual Math Teams (VMT) enable public interaction and those interactions remain publicly available. This published material, available to the public, may include your name if you include it in your submissions. Researchers may study this data in order to understand online learning and instruction.
  * If you use a credit card to purchase a Math Forum product on our site, we do not save your credit card information.

At any time you may request the removal of your name or other personal information and contributions by e-mailing us or by contacting us via postal mail or telephone (800)756-7823.

We want to be very clear: We will not obtain personal identifying information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to provide such information to us.

We do not sell or rent our customer names, addresses, or other information to third parties for any purpose.

This site contains links to other sites. The Math Forum is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

### Public Forums

This site makes mailing lists, Web discussion forums, live chats (VMT) and message boards available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public, and that you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. The Math Forum reserves the right to remove any posting that its editors consider inappropriate. The Math Forum may support researchers who study activity in the public forums if their research is governed by accountable Institutional Review Boards (IRBs).

* * *

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us.

**Postal address:**  
The Math Forum  
3210 Cherry Street  
Philadelphia, PA 19104
